

Technical Lead and Sr. Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Cloud Computing, Product Development, Agile Methodology, Technical Architecture, Client Management, Full Stack Development



Current Designation: Technical Lead and Sr. Developer Total Experience: 13 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Applied Information Sciences Inc. Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Delhi / NCR, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Technical Lead and Sr. Developer, Team Lead/Tech Lead, Software Development, Application

Programming, Cloud Computing, Product Development, Agile Methodology, Technical Architecture, Client Management, Full

Stack Development

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

13 years of professional experience in Full-Stack software development, recognized for conceptual excellence and the ability to handle challenging assignments.

Experience in developing and implementing Web and Cloud based systems using .Net Core, Restful Web API, MVC, Asp.Net, Web Services, WCF, SQL server, EntityFramework, kafka, NoSql

Hands-on programming experience in C#, Angular, JavaScript, Typescript, Nodejs, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Jade, Bootstrap Having good knowledge on implementing Microservices based architecture

Experience in version controls and repos like TFS, GitHub, Sourcetree etc.

Good Knowledge on data structures and algorithms

Experience working in collaboration with product development teams using Agile/Scrum

In-depth background analyzing business requirements and recommending appropriate technologies.

Professional understanding of System development life cycle SDLC as well as various phases such as Analysis Design, Development and Testing.

Work Experience

Applied Information Sciences Inc. as Technical Lead and Sr. Developer Jun 2012 to Till Date

Technical Lead and Sr. Developer WALMART-WARP(Domain - eCommerce)? Sept 2015 to Present Responsible for Development, Upgrades, Optimization, implementing and troubleshooting Walmart applications that are part of activation as per clients requirements. WARP is an eCommerce mobile activation application that runs in pos systems of all 10000+ WALMART Stores of US. Technically this project involves work on: Angular 6, C#.Net, Core.Net, Restful Web API, JavaScript, Nodejs, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Gulp, SQL Server, CouchDB, WCF, MVC using the tools Visual Code, TFS 2012, VS 2012, VS 2015, VS 2017, GitHub, Nuget.

Developer, GIECO-Policy(Domain? Insurance)? Jun 2012 to Aug 2015

Responsible for Development and Enhancements. The project is a WCF exposing HTTP Endpoints to trigger different transactions (New Business, Amendment etc.). These endpoints would be consumed by other teams that would collect the required data from user interfaces. Technically this project involves work on: C# .Net 4.0, WCF, MVC4, JavaScript, Jquery, LINQ, TFS, StructureMap, Nuget, StyleCop using tools TFS 2012, VS 2012.

TATA Consultancy Services as Module Lead Jan 2011 to May 2012

Responsible lead for application deployment support for British Telecom UK Business Strategic Training Environment application. Responsible for deploying and supporting the software development projects of a six person team. Responsible for day-day sanity checks for training environment, identify, evaluate and fix any issues. This project technically involves work on: C#, Asp.net, WCF, Javascript and tools ZXTM, BRIDGE CLARIFY, Putty, Web logic Developer - EIRCOM(Domain - Telecom) - Jan 2009 to Dec 2010

Responsible for developing touchscreen application that help billing, reporting etc. Responsible for handling the Unit testing, integration testing setup creation and patch deployment rollout to all existing vendors. This project technical involves work on: ASP .Net 2.0,.Net 3.5, C#, ADO.Net win forms, Crystal Reports, SQL Server 2005, Visual Studio 2005, SVN, Microsoft VSS.

Developer- FUJIXEROX-Image Gateway Document Conversion(Domain - Printing) - Mar 2007 to Dec 2008 Responsible for development of Document conversion service application that converts scanned input from a multi function device (printer) to readable format that should support multiple languages. Responsible in fixing issues post release to the clients. This project technically involves work on : Visual Studio 2005 C# ASP.Net 2.0 , SQL server 2005 using tools Omni page CSDK 16 ,Omni page professional, Install shield etc.

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Osmania University in 2003

PG: MCA (Computers) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2006

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
C#, VB.Net, Typescript, javacript			
ASP.NET WEBAPI, ASP.NET MVC			
ASP.NET Web, WCF, Web Services			
Angular, Node			
JavaScript, CSS, Jquery, Ajax			
Twitter Bootstrap			
Factory, Singleton, Adapter, Bridge			
Repository, MVC			
Structure Map			
Exposure on - Azure Cognitive Services			
Azure Services, Azure application			
insights, CI/CD			
TFS, GIT, SourceTree, BitBucket			
VS 2017 and lower versions			
TFS Work Items, JIRA			
TFS, CI/CD			
SQL Server, CouchDB			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time